PROFILE

I am an interaction designer who is passionate about my craft. I create digital experiences for desktop and mobile devices. In my 9-year career, I have worked for and with businesses using my skills to strategically plan and execute user-focused digital experiences. I am available for a position where I can collaborate with and lead others passionate about digital and use my experience and innate abilities to enhance the digital efforts of a progressive company.

EXPERIENCE

INTERACTION DESIGN MANAGER

Oakley, Inc.; Foothill Ranch, CA

2015-current

- Leading the Interaction Design team responsible for UI/UX and front-end for Oakley digital properties (oakley.com, apps & wearables, training tools) across all devices
- Providing design and front-end development direction for team members, driving each project while enabling the success of each designer/developer
- Collaborating with cross-functional teams (Marketing, Product, Merchandising) to build digital strategies and align with other teams for a fully integrated experience
- Creating responsive user interface designs, developing responsive front-end templates (HTML, CSS, JavaScript) and integrating with a back-end system (CraftCMS).

INTERACTION DESIGNER

Oakley, Inc.; Foothill Ranch, CA

2013-2015

- Led digital creative (UI) and partnered with a 3rd-party vendor (Intel) to build a multi-platform native app and wearable product
- Executed UX/UI for Oakley digital properties (oakley.com, apps & wearables, training tools) across all devices
- Created responsive user interface designs, developing responsive front-end templates (HTML, CSS, JavaScript) and integrated with a back-end system (CraftCMS).

FREELANCE WEB DESIGNER/DEVELOPER, OWNER

Virtue Interactive; Orange County, CA

2010-current

- Building and maintaining (UI, UX, front-end development and back-end integration) websites for clientele nationwide across multiple industries
- Consulting businesses for digital strategy and execution

MULTIMEDIA SPECIALIST

Uftring Marketing Group; Peoria, IL

2012-2013

- Developed and maintained 6+ websites for a large local auto dealership group
- Concepted and created marketing materials for web, email, social media, print, email and billboards
- Improved search engine marketing and optimization

WEB DESIGNER/DEVELOPER

V Gallery; Morton, IL

2008-2010

- Built and maintained a Magento-based e-commerce website and deployed supporting websites for a world-renowned professional photography studio
- Planned and executed web- and location-based promotions at international and domestic trade shows
- Planned and executed a social media engagement strategy to increase brand awareness in a developing market

WEB DESIGNER/DEVELOPER

MComm Group; Peoria Heights, IL

2007-2008

- Designed and developed trade show promotional website for a major international construction equipment company
- Assisted marketing coordinator by interfacing and maintaining relationships with clients
- Designed and co-managed product launch campaigns for a retail e-commerce oriented business
- Built and maintained websites for national construction and agricultural equipment dealers
- Built and maintained websites for national clientele across multiple industries

EDUCATION

BRADLEY UNIVERSITY

Peoria, Illinois — B.A., Communication with a specialization in Advertising and Marketing

ILLINOIS CENTRAL COLLEGE

East Peoria, Illinois — Associate's Degree and Web Designer Certificate

SKILLS

Communicating and articulating ideas. User experience and visual design (UX/UI). Prototyping. HTML, CSS/SASS, JavaScript, Adobe Photoshop, Sketch, Sublime Text/Atom and Git. Top 5 StrengthsFinder strengths: empathy, restorative, activator, developer, harmony

LATEST WORK

See http://dribbble.com/nathanroberts